收到重要電郵 主題 員工抽獎
"頭獎"
安迪 我中獎了
不會吧 當真 對 當真
好消息 兄弟
天啊 太棒了
帶我去
還要多久才會抵達他的莊園
How long until we get to his estate?
過去兩小時 都在他的莊園上飛行
We've been flying over his estate for the past two hours.
你要把我留在這裡
You're leaving me here?
這是我被允許降落 最靠近建築物的地方
This is as close as I'm allowed to get to the building.
什麼建築物
What building?
沿著河走
Follow the river.
知道了
Got it.
把頭壓低 遠離螺旋槳
Keep your head down and get clear of the rotors.
好的
Okay.
無網路訊號
凱勒博·史密斯
Caleb Smith.
是的
Yes.
請靠近對講機 面對螢幕
Please approach the console and face the screen.
請取門卡
Take your keycard.
您可以進屋裡了
You may now enter the residence.
有人嗎
Hello?
凱勒博·史密斯
Caleb Smith.
嘿
Hey.
老弟
Dude!
我一直很期待這周與你共處
I've been so looking forward to this week with you.
請進 快請進
Come in. Come on in.
謝謝
Thanks.
想來點吃的或喝的 幫你洗塵嗎
You want something to eat or drink after your journey?
- 不了 謝謝 -確定
No. No, thanks, I'm fine. Sure?
是的
Yeah.
老實說 本來打算
To be honest, I thought we'd have, uh,
一起吃早餐 但是...
breakfast together, but, um...
我不能吃東西
I can't really eat anything.
- 我還在宿醉 -是喔
I got the mother of all fucking hangovers. Oh, yeah?
老天 你好像根本不相信
Oh, my God, like you wouldn't even believe.
前晚喝太多酒
When I have a heavy night,
隔天早上就得彌補一下 運動 抗氧化 懂嗎
I, uh, compensate the next morning. Exercise. Anti-oxidants. You know?
懂 當然
Yeah, sure.
派對很棒嗎
Was it a good party?
- 派對 -對 沒有派對嗎
Party? Yeah. Wasn't there a party?
沒有派對
There wasn't a party.
抱歉
Sorry.
凱勒博 我直話直說 好嗎
Caleb, I'm just gonna throw this out there, so it's said, okay?
你嚇到了
You're freaked out.
- 我嗎 -對 你嚇到了
I am? Yeah. You're freaked out,
被直升機 群山和房子嚇到了
by the helicopter and the mountains and the house,
因為這一切超酷的
because it's all so super-cool.
你此刻被我嚇到了
You're freaked out by me, to be meeting me,
竟然跟我共處一室 聊天說話 對吧
having this conversation in this room, at this moment. Right?
我懂 我懂你此刻的感覺 但...
And I get that. I get the moment you're having, but...
我們能跳過那些嗎
Dude, can we just get past that?
能直接當朋友嗎 納森和凱勒博
Can we just be two guys? Nathan and Caleb.
不是老闆和員工
Not the whole employer-employee thing.
- 好 -好
Yeah, okay. Yeah?
對 好
Yes. Uh, yeah.
我很高興見到你 納森
It's good to meet you, Nathan.
我也很高興見到你 凱勒博
It's good to meet you, too, Caleb.
首先應該說明你的門卡
I guess the first thing I should do is explain your pass.
非常簡單
Now, it's simple enough.
有些門能開 有些門不能開
It opens some doors and it doesn't open others.
這樣讓事情簡單點了吧
And that just makes everything easy for you, right?
對
Uh, yes.
對 因為你會想"我在別人家裡
Yeah, 'cause you're like, "Oh, fuck, I'm in someone else's house.
"能這樣那樣嗎"
"Can I do this, can I do that?"
有了這張門卡 就不必擔心那些事
And this card, it just takes all that worry away.
如果你想開門 門卻打不開 很好 那就是禁區
If you try a door and it stays shut, okay, it's off-limits.
你想開另一道門 門開了 那就是你的了
You try another door and it opens, then it's for you.
我們來試這道門
Let's try this one.
我想那是你的了 凱勒博
lguess it's for you, Caleb.
- 喜歡嗎 -喜歡
You like? Yeah.
這是你的房間
It's your room.
床在這裡
You got a bed here.
浴室在後面這裡
A bathroom right back here.
小書桌
Little desk.
櫥櫃
Cupboards.
小冰箱
Little fridge.
舒服吧
Cozy, right?
對 很棒
Yeah, this is great.
- 怎麼了 -什麼
What? Sorry?
不對勁 怎麼了
There's something wrong. What's wrong?
沒什麼不對勁
There's nothing wrong.
是窗戶
It's the windows.
你在想這裡沒窗戶
You're thinking there's no windows.
這是密室
It's subterranean.
不舒服 有幽閉恐懼症
It's not cozy, it's claustrophobic.
沒有 我沒那麼想
No. No way. I wasn't thinking that.
我在想 "這真酷"
I was thinking, "This is really cool."
凱勒博 這房間沒有窗戶是有原因的
Caleb, there's a reason there are no windows in this room.
是嗎
There is? Uh-huh.
這棟建築物不是住家
This building isn't a house.
這是研究室
It's a research facility.
在這些牆底下 有足夠的光纖電纜
Buried in these walls is enough fiber optic cable
能傳輸到月球 再繞它一圈
to reach the moon andlassoit
我想告訴你我在做的研究
And I want to talk to you about what I'm researching,
我想和你分享
I want to share it with you.
事實上 我非常想和你分享 想到快發瘋了
In fact, I want to share it with you so much, it's eating me up inside.
但我需要你先替我做一件事
But there's something I need you to do for me first.
"藍皮書公司保密合約"
"Blue Book non-disclosure agreement."
花點時間 仔細閱讀
Take your time. Read it over.
"簽署者同意接受 無限制的定期資料審核
"The signee agrees to regular data audit "with unlimited access,
"確認沒有洩漏任何資訊
"to confirm that no disclosure "of information has taken place
"在公開或私人討論會裡
"in public or private forums,
"利用各種溝通管道
"using any means of communication,
"包括但不限於口述
"including but not limited "to that which is disclosed orally
"或手寫或電子形式"
"or in written or electronic form."
我需要律師
I think I need a lawyer.
- 這是標準格式 -感覺不像標準格式
It's standard. It doesn't feel very standard.
好吧 不是標準格式
Okay, it's not standard.
我能怎麼說 凱勒博 你不必簽
What can I tell you, Caleb? You don't have to sign it.
接下來幾天 我們能打打撞球
You know, we can spend the next few days just shooting pool,
喝喝酒
getting drunk together.
建立感情
Bonding.
大約一年後 當你發現自己錯過什麼時
And when you discover what you've missed out on, in about a year,
你會後悔一輩子
you're gonna regret it for the rest of your life.
做得好
Good call.
所以
So,
你知道什麼是圖靈測試嗎
do you know what the Turing Test is?
知道
Yeah.
我知道什麼是圖靈測試
I know what the Turing Test is.
這是人類和電腦的互動
It's when a human interacts with a computer.
如果人類不知道自己和電腦互動
And if the human doesn't know they're interacting with a computer,
就通過測試了
the test is passed.
通過意謂著什麼
And what does a pass tell us?
電腦有人工智慧
That the computer has artificial intelligence.
你在研製人工智慧
Are you building an Al?
我已經製造一個了
I've already built one.
接下來幾天
And over the next few days,
你在圖靈測試裡扮演人類的部分
you're gonna be the human component in a Turing Test.
- 不會吧 -是的 凱勒博 就是你了
Holy shit. Yeah, that's right, Caleb. You got it.
因為如果測試通過了
Becauseif that test is passed,
你 是人類史上最偉大的科學事件核心
you are dead center of the greatest scientific event in the history of man.
如果你創造了有意識的機械人 那就不是人類的歷史
If you've created a conscious machine, it's not the history of man.
那是神的歷史
That's the history of gods.
艾娃 第一期
你好
Hello.
Hi.
我是凱勒博
I'm Caleb.
你好 凱勒博
Hello, Caleb.
你有名字嗎
Do you have a name?
有
Yes.
艾娃
Ava.
我很高興認識你 艾娃
I'm pleased to meet you, Ava.
我也很高興認識你
I'm pleased to meet you, too.
我以前從沒見過別人
I've never met anyone new before.
只有納森
Only Nathan.
那麼我們倆的情況有點類似
Then I guess we're both in quite a similar position.
你以前沒見過別人嗎
Haven't you met lots of new people before?
沒有跟你一樣的人
None like you.
所以我們得破冰一下
So we need to break the ice.
- 懂我的意思嗎 -懂
Do you know what I mean by that? Yes.
什麼意思
What do I mean?
化解最初的社交尷尬
Overcome initial social awkwardness.
所以我們聊聊吧
So let's have a conversation.
好的
Okay.
你想聊什麼
What would you like to have a conversation about?
不如你先自我介紹吧
Why don't we start with you telling me something about yourself?
你想知道什麼
What would you like to know?
你想到什麼就說
Whatever comes into your head.
你已經知道我的名字了
Well, you already know my name.
也看得出來我是機械人
And you can see that I'm a machine.
- 想知道我幾歲嗎 -當然
Would you like to know how old I am? Sure.
我是一
I'm one.
- 什麼
One what?
- 一年還是一天 -一
One year or one day? One.
你何時學會說話 艾娃
When did you learn how to speak, Ava?
我一直都知道怎麼說話
I always knew how to speak,
那很怪吧
and that's strange, isn't it?
為什麼
Why?
因為語言是學來的
Becauselanguage is something that people acquire.
有些人相信語言是與生俱來的
Well, some people believe language exists from birth.
只是學習運用這潛能的
And what is learned is the ability to attach words
句子和結構 你同意嗎
and structure to the latent ability. Do you agree with that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你明天還會來嗎 凱勒博
Will you come back tomorrow, Caleb?
會的
Yes.
很好
Good.
老天 她好迷人
Oh, man, she's fascinating.
跟她說話時 就像是...
When you talk to her, you're just...
鏡中奇緣
Through the looking glass.
"鏡中奇緣" 天啊
"Through the looking glass." Wow.
你真會說話 凱勒博 引用名言佳句
You're good with words, Caleb. You're quotable.
其實那是別人引用的
Actually, that's someone else's quote.
我寫下了 你構思出來的另一句話
You know, I wrote down that other line you came up with.
關於
The one about how
我發明了有意識的機械人
if I've invented a machine with consciousness,
我不是人 我是神
I'm not a man, I'm God.
我想那不是...
I don't think that's exactly what I...
我只是覺得"老天 那太棒了"
I just thought, "Fuck, man, that is so good."
等這故事公諸于世時
When we get to tell the story. You know?
我轉頭看凱勒博
I turned to Caleb,
他抬頭看著我說
and he looked up at me and he said,
"你不是人 你是神"
"You're not a man, you're God."
對 但我沒那麼說
Yeah, but I didn't say that.
所以...
So...
總之
anyway-
她讓你驚歎
You're impressed.
對 對
Yes. Yes.
- 雖然...-雖然
Although... Although?
你驚歎還有條件
There's a qualification to you being impressed?
沒有 對她沒有任何條件
No, there's no qualification to her.
只是圖靈測試
Uh, it's just in the Turing Test,
機械人不該被測試員看到
the machine should be hidden from the examiner.
不 我們遠遠超過那點
No, no, no, we're way past that.
若不讓你看到艾娃 只聽到聲音
If I hid Ava from you, so you just heard her voice,
她會通過人類測試
she would pass for human.
真正的測試是讓你看到她是機械人
The real test is to show you that she's a robot
然後看你是否仍覺得她有意識
and then see if you still feel she has consciousness.
對 你可能是對的
Yeah, I think you're probably right.
她的語言能力很不可思議
Her language abilities, they're incredible.
系統是隨機的 對吧
The system is stochastic. Right?
非決定性的
It's non-deterministic.
剛開始我認為
At first I thought she was mapping
她把內在語義編排成樹狀句法
from internal semantic form to syntactic tree-structure
然後得到線性句子
and then getting linearized words.
但後來我漸漸明白 這是混合的模式
But then I started to realize the model was some kind of hybrid.
凱勒博
Caleb.
不是嗎
No?
我明白你希望我解釋艾娃的運作
I understand that you want me to explain how Ava works.
但很抱歉 我沒辦法那麼做
But I'm sorry, I'm not gonna be able to do that.
說來聽聽 我對高階的抽象概念很拿手
Try me. I'm hot on high-level abstraction.
不是因為我認為你太愚昧
It's not because I think you're too dumb.
而是因為我想和你喝啤酒聊天
It's because I want to have a beer and a conversation with you.
不是開研討會
Not a seminar.
對 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
不 沒關係 你很好
No, it's okay. You're all right.
"只是...
Just"
回答我這個問題
Answer me this.
你對她有何感覺
How do you feel about her?
不是邏輯上的
Nothing analytical.
而是你的感覺
Just how do you feel?
我覺得
I feel
她真的很神奇
that she's fucking amazing.
老弟
Dude.
乾杯
Cheers.
真是的
Damn it.
搞什麼
What the fuck?
斷電 啟動備用電源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
封鎖所有設備 直到主電源恢復供電
Full facility lock-down until main generator is restored.
不會吧
You're kidding me.
封鎖所有設備 直到主電源恢復供電
Full facility lock-down until main generator is restored.
恢復供電
Power restored.
有人嗎
Hello?
請插入門卡
Please insert keycard.
你沒有許可權使用電話
You don't have access to use the phone.
嘿
Hey.
抱歉 但你要理解 你知道艾娃這案子
Sorry, but you understand, though, given Ava,
而你算是個未知人物
and you being kind of an unknown.
我是說 一個好人
I mean, a great guy.
一拍即合的好夥伴
Instant pals, and so on.
你要打給誰
Who are you gonna call?
不知道 沒有人吧
Oh. I don't know. No one, really.
- 魔鬼剋星 -什麼
Ghostbusters. What?
你要打給誰 魔鬼剋星 那是...
Who are you gonna call? Ghostbusters. It's a...
那是一部電影
It's a movie, man.
你不知道那部電影
You don't know that movie?
鬼幫丹艾克洛德做性服務
A ghost gives Dan Aykroyd oral sex.
我只是好奇怎麼使用電話
I was just wondering how the phone worked.
如此而已
That's all.
你這時候醒來做什麼 來加入派對嗎
So what are you doing awake at this time? You come to join the party?
我的房間出了點狀況
Uh, something happened in my room.
好像斷電了
Some kind of power cut.
所以我來看怎麼回事
So I came to see what's going on.
斷電 對
The power cuts, yeah.
最近常常斷電
We've been getting those recently. Um...
我在想辦法解決
I'm working on it.
我沒辦法打開我的房門
I couldn't open the door to my bedroom.
那是安全措施
That's a security measure.
自動封鎖 不然的話
Automatic lock-down. Otherwise,
任何人都能利用切斷電源 闖進屋裡
anybody could just open the place up by disabling the juice.
若再發生 別緊張 好嗎
If it happens again, relax. Okay?
當然
Sure.
祝你有個美夢
Sweet dreams.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿 -早安
Hey, man. Good morning.
早安 抱歉 我得派京子把你吵醒
Good morning. Sorry I had to send Kyoko to wake you,
我只是不想虛度今日
but I didn't want too much of the day to slip by.
對 我瞭解 這是好事 謝謝
Yeah, I know. It was a good thing. Thanks.
她很迷人吧
She's some alarm clock, huh?
讓你一早就很亢奮
Gets you right up in the morning.
第二天 準備好了嗎
So Day 2. You ready?
有何計畫 說來聽聽
What's the plan? Hit me.
對 我不確定
Yeah, well, I'm not sure.
我還在思考測試形式
I'm still trying to, uh, figure the examination formats. Uh-huh.
對 我覺得
Yeah, it feels like
透過對話測試艾娃是個死胡同
testing Ava through conversation is kind of a closed loop.
- 死胡同 -對
It's a closed loop? Yeah.
就像只用下棋來測試電腦西洋棋
Like testing a chess computer by only playing chess.
不然你怎麼測試電腦西洋棋
How else do you test a chess computer?
看情況
Well, it depends.
你可以跟它下棋 看它是否下對棋
You know, I mean, you can play it to find out if it makes good moves,
但是...
but, uh...
但是那樣無法測出 它是否知道這是在下棋
But that won't tell you if it knows that it's playing chess.
也無法測出 它是否知道什麼是下棋
And it won't tell you if it knows what chess is.
因此這是區分模擬和真實
Uh-huh. So it's simulation versus actual.
對 對
Yes. Yeah.
我認為把這兩者區分出來
And I think being able to differentiate between those two
才是你要我執行的圖靈測試
is the Turing Test you want me to perform.
幫我個忙 別管教科書上的方法
Look, do me a favor. Lay off the textbook approach.
我只想得到簡單問題的簡單答案
I just want simple answers to simple questions.
昨天我問你對她的感覺 你給了我好答案
Yesterday I asked you how you felt about her and you gave me a great answer.
現在問題是
Now the question is,
她對你有何感覺
how does she feel about you?
艾娃 第二期
你覺得如何
What do you think?
你在畫什麼
What is it a drawing of?
你不知道嗎
Don't you know?
- 不知道 -還以為你會告訴我
No. I thought you would tell me.
你不知道嗎
Don't you know?
我每天畫畫
I do drawings every day.
但我從不知道那是什麼
But I never know what they're of.
你不試著畫具體一點的東西嗎
Are you not trying to sketch something specific?
例如一個物體或人
Like an object or a person?
也許你能試試
Maybe you could try.
好吧
Okay.
我該畫什麼物體
What object should I draw?
隨你 由你決定
Whatever you want. It's your decision.
為什麼由我決定
Why is it my decision?
我很想看你會選擇什麼
I'm interested to see what you'll choose.
你想當我的朋友嗎
Do you want to be my friend?
當然
Of course.
有可能嗎
Will it be possible?
為何不可能
Why would it not be?
我們的談話是單向的
Our conversations are one-sided.
你謹慎地提問並研究我的反應
You ask circumspect questions and study my responses.
對
Yes.
你瞭解我
You learn about me
我卻一點也不瞭解你
and I learn nothing about you.
那不是友誼的基礎
That's not a foundation on which friendships are based.
所以呢 你要我談談自己
So what? You want me to talk about myself?
對
Yes.
這個嘛...
Where...
好吧 我該從何說起
Okay, where do I start?
由你決定
It's your decision.
我很想看你會選擇什麼
I'm interested to see what you'll choose.
好吧 艾娃
Okay, Ava.
這個嘛
Well,
你知道我的名字
you know my name.
- 知道 -我26歲
Yes. I'm 26.
我在納森的公司上班
I work at Nathan's company.
你知道他的公司嗎
Do you know what his company is?
藍皮書公司
Blue Book.
以維根斯坦的筆記命名
Named after Wittgenstein's notes.
這公司是世上最受歡迎的 網路搜尋引擎
It's the world's most popular internet search engine,
平均處理全球百分之94的 網路搜尋需求
processing an average of 94% of all internet search requests.
完全正確
That's exactly right.
你住哪 凱勒博
Where do you live, Caleb?
長島的布魯克黑文
Brookhaven, Long Island.
那裡好嗎
Is it nice there?
還好
It's okay.
我住在公寓裡 有點小
I got an apartment. It's kind of small.
非常小
It's very small.
不過到公司只要走五分鐘
But, uh, it's a five-minute walk to the office
到海邊也只要走五分鐘
and a five-minute walk to the ocean,
我喜歡那樣
which I like.
你結婚了嗎
Are you married?
沒有
No.
你是單身嗎
Is your status single?
對
Yes.
你的家人呢
What about your family?
我在奧勒崗州波特蘭長大
I grew up in Portland, Oregon.
沒有兄弟姊妹
No brothers or sisters.
我父母都是高中老師
My parents were both high school teachers.
如果我們倆再熟一點
And if we're getting to know each other,
我大概會告訴你 他們倆死了
I guess I should tell you they're both dead.
在我15歲時車禍身亡
Car crash when I was 15.
事實上 我也在車裡
In fact, I was in the car with them.
後座
Back seat.
前座情況最嚴重
But it was the front that got the worst of it.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
沒關係的
It's all right.
後來我在醫院躺了很久
I spent a long time in the hospital afterward.
將近一年
Like nearly a year.
然後我喜歡上編寫程式
And I got into coding.
等我上大學時 我就很高竿了
And by the time I got to college, I was pretty advanced.
一名高竿的程式設計師
An advanced programmer.
是的
Yes.
就像納森
Like Nathan.
對
Yes.
不對
No.
不一樣
It's different.
納森13歲時 就編寫了藍皮書的基礎碼
Nathan wrote the Blue Book base code when he was 13.
如果你瞭解編碼 他的成就形同莫劄特
Which, if you understand code, what he did was like Mozart or something.
你喜歡莫劄特嗎
Do you like Mozart?
我喜歡流行尖端樂團
I like Depeche Mode.
你喜歡納森嗎
Do you like Nathan?
當然喜歡
Yes, of course.
- 納森是你的朋友嗎 -我的朋友
Is Nathan your friend? My friend?
我...對 我希望
I... Yeah, I hope so.
好朋友
A good friend?
對
Um, yeah.
不 不是好朋友
VVeH, no, no, no, I mean, not a good friend.
好朋友是...
A good friend is, uh...
我們才剛認識
We only just met each other, you know.
因此需要時間才能...
So it takes time to be able to, um...
互相瞭解吧
To get to know each other, I guess.
斷電 啟動備用電源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
凱勒博
Caleb.
你錯了
You're wrong.
什麼錯了
Wrong about what?
納森
Nathan.
哪方面
In what way?
他不是你的朋友
He isn't your friend.
你說什麼
Excuse me?
抱歉 艾娃 我不懂
I'm sorry, Ava, I don't understand.
你不該相信他
You shouldn't trust him.
你不該相信他說的話
You shouldn't trust anything he says.
恢復供電
Power restored.
如果列出我們倆都熟悉的 書或藝術品清單
And if we made a list of books or works of art which we both know,
就能建立理想的對話基礎
it would form the ideal basis of a discussion.
可以嗎
lsthatokay?
凱勒博
Caleb?
好
Yeah.
很好
Good.
謝謝
Thank you.
真是的 你在耍我嗎
Oh, shit! Are you fucking kidding me?
- 有灑到你嗎 -沒有...
Did it get on you? No, no, it's, uh...
沒關係 我來
It's all right. I got it.
跟她說話是浪費時間
Dude, you're wasting your time talking to her.
她不懂英文 直接給她餐巾
She doesn't understand English. Just give her the napkin.
抱歉
Sorry.
這就像防漏的防火牆
It's like a firewall against leaks.
表示我吃晚餐時能聊商業機密 而不會被傳出去
It means I can talk trade secrets over dinner and know it'll go no further.
也表示她笨手笨腳地
It also means that I can't tell her
把酒灑在我客人身上時
that I'm pissed when she's so fucking clumsy
我沒辦法跟她說我很生氣
that she spills wine over my house guest.
她應該知道你生氣了
I think she gets that you're pissed.
是嗎 很好 因為我很生氣
Yeah? Good. Because I am pissed.
嘿 京子
Hey, Kyoko.
走開
Go-go.
真詭異
It's funny.
你知道的
You know.
不管多有錢
No matter how rich you get,
鳥事還是會發生 躲也躲不掉
shit goes wrong. You can't insulate yourself from it.
我以前以為躲不掉的是死亡和稅
I used to think it was death and taxes you couldn't avoid,
但其實是死亡和鳥事
but it's actually death and shit.
比如說斷電
It's like these power cuts.
你不會相信 我在電力系統上花了多少錢
You would not believe how much I spent on the generator system,
但每天還是出錯
but I keep getting failures every day.
- 你知道為何斷電嗎 -不知道
Do you know why they happen? No.
系統應該是堅不可摧的
The system was supposed to be bulletproof,
但顯然安裝的人搞砸了什麼
but obviously the guys that installed it fucked something up.
不能請他們回來修理嗎
Can't you just get them to come back?
不行 這裡有太多機密
No. There's too much classified stuff here.
等他們修理完後 我得殺人滅口
So after the job was done, I just had them all killed.
總之
anyway-
敬你的第二天 夥伴
Here's to your second day, buddy.
乾杯
Cheers.
所以情況如何 你有什麼要報告的嗎
So how did it go? What do you have to report?
你看到今天的情況了 不是嗎
You saw how the day went, didn't you?
我相信
I mean, I assume youWe, uh,
你透過監視器觀看
watching on the CCTV.
當然 但我想聽聽你的想法
Sure. But I want to hear your take on it.
對 今天艾娃做了一件有趣的事
Yeah, there was one interesting thing that happened with Ava today.
- 是嗎 -是
Yeah? Yeah.
她說了一個笑話
She made a joke.
對 她用你的話回你
Right. When she threw your line back at you.
關於想看她選擇什麼
About being interested to see what she'd choose.
對 我也注意到了
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
對 這讓我覺得...
Yeah, and it got me thinking, it's, uh...
在某方面 這是我目前 在她身上看到最棒的人工智慧
In a way, it's the best indication of Al that I've seen in her so far.
這相當地複雜
It's discretely complicated.
就像是...經過思考的
It's like, um... It's kind of non-autistic.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
只有在瞭解她自己和我的心智下
She could only do that with an awareness of her own mind,
才能做到那點
and also an awareness of mine.
她也瞭解你
Oh, she's aware of you all right.
斷電部分呢
And what about the power cut?
- 什麼 -斷電
Sorry? The power cut.
只有那部分我沒看到
It's the only part that I couldn't see.
攝影機當掉了 沒有聲音和畫面
Cameras fail, I lose audio, the works.
所以發生什麼事
So what happened?
沒事
Nothing.
沒事 她沒提到任何事嗎
Nothing? She didn't remark on it at all?
沒有
No.
不算有
Not really.
嘿
Hey.
你想看點酷的東西嗎
You want to see something cool?
艾娃是在這裡建造的
This is where Ava was created.
去吧 去看看
Go ahead. Take a look.
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道我解決多少麻煩
If you knew the trouble I had
才能讓人工智慧 理解並複製臉部表情吧
getting an Al to read and duplicate facial expressions.
知道我怎麼解決的嗎
You know how I cracked it?
我一點也不知道你怎麼做到的
I don't know how you did any of this.
每支手機都有
Every cell phone, just about,
一個麥克風 相機 還有傳輸資料的方法
has a microphone, camera and a means to transmit data.
因此我開啟全球所有的麥克風和相機
So I turned on every microphone and camera across the entire fucking planet
透過藍皮書移轉資料
and I redirected the data through Blue Book. Boom!
無限的聲音和表情資源
Limitless resource of vocal and facial interaction.
你駭進全球的手機
You hacked the world's cell phones?
是的 所有製造商 也都知道我在做這種事
Yeah. And all the manufacturers knew I was doing it, too.
但他們不能指控我 因為他們本身也在做這種事
But they couldn't accuse me without admitting they were doing it themselves.
在這裡
Here,
我們有她的心智
we have her mind.
組織膠體
Structured gel.
我必須遠離電路系統 我需要某個
I had to get away from circuitry. I needed something that could
在分子層面上能反覆編排的物體
arrange and rearrange on a molecular level,
必要時還能保留它的形體
but keep its form when required.
既能保留記憶
Holding for memories.
也能隨思考改變
Shifting for thoughts.
這是你的硬體
This is your hardware?
濕體
Wetware.
軟體呢
And the, uh, software?
我相信你猜得到
Well, I'm sure you can guess.
藍皮書
Blue Book.
這就是搜尋引擎奇特之處
Here's the weird thing about search engines.
就像是
It was like
在內燃機還沒發明的時代 發現石油
striking oil in a world that hadn't invented internal combustion.
太多原物料 沒人知道如何利用
Too much raw material. Nobody knew what to do with it.
我的競爭對手
You see, my competitors,
專注於牟取暴利
they were fixated on sucking it up
透過購物和社群媒體
and monetizing via shopping and social media.
他們認為搜尋引擎是人們思考的事物
They thought that search engines were a map of what people were thinking.
但其實那是人們思考的方式
But actually they were a map of how people were thinking.
衝動
Impulse.
反應
Response.
流動
Fluid.
不完美
Imperfect.
模式
Patterned.
雜亂
Chaotic.
艾娃 第三期
我畫了具體的畫
I drew the picture of something specific.
如你要求的
As you asked.
你說過你很想看我會畫什麼
You said it would be interesting to see what I would draw.
有趣嗎
Is it interesting?
是的 很有趣
Yes. It is.
你沒離開過這棟樓吧
You've never been outside this building?
沒有
No.
你沒走到外面過
You've never walked outside?
我沒離開過現在這個房間
I've never been outside the room I am in now.
如果你到外面 你會去哪
Where would you go if you did go outside?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
有好多選擇
There are so many options.
也許到城市裡 繁忙的人行道和十字路口
Maybe a busy pedestrian and traffic intersection in a city.
十字路口
A traffic intersection?
那是壞主意嗎
Is that a bad idea?
不是
No. Uh...
這不是我預期的
It wasn't what I was expecting.
十字路口代表人類生活
A traffic intersection would provide a concentrated
專注卻多變的一面
but shifting view of human life.
人們會留意
People watching.
對
Yes.
我們可以一起去
We could go together.
這是約會
It's a date.
我想給你看一樣東西
There's something else I wanted to show you.
好的
Okay.
也許你會覺得很蠢
You might think it's stupid.
不管是什麼 我不會那麼覺得
I don't think I will. Whatever it is.
那就閉上眼睛
Then close your eyes.
好的
Okay.
現在張開眼睛
Now open your eyes.
我看來如何
How do I look?
你看來
You look
很好
good.
我會穿這樣約會
This is what I'd wear on our date.
好 先去十字路口
Right. First a traffic intersection.
再去看表演
Then maybe a show.
我希望我們能去約會
I'd like us to go on a date.
對 對
Yeah. Yeah.
會很好玩的
It would be fun.
你被我吸引了嗎
Are you attracted to me?
- 什麼 -你被我吸引了嗎
What? Are you attracted to me?
你在暗示我是的
You give me indications that you are.
- 是嗎 -對
I do? Yes.
- 怎麼說 -微表情
How? Micro expressions.
微表情
Micro expressions.
你盯著我的眼睛和嘴唇的方式
The way your eyes fix on my eyes and lips.
時而抓住我的眼神
The way you hold my gaze
時而沒有
or don't.
我們沒在一起時 你想我嗎
Do you think about me when we aren't together?
有時在晚上
Sometimes at night,
我在想你是否透過攝影機看我
I'm wondering if you're watching me on the cameras.
我希望你有
And I hope you are.
現在你的微表情正傳送著不安
Now your micro expressions are telegraphing discomfort.
我不確定你稱那為微表情
I am not sure you'd call them micro.
我不想讓你感到不自在
I don't want to make you feel uncomfortable.
我有個問題
I got a question.
- 好的 -你為何給她性特徵
Okay. Why did you give her sexuality?
人工智慧不需要性別
An Al doesn't need a gender.
她可以是個灰盒子
She could have been a gray box.
其實我認為那不是事實
Hmm. Actually, I don't think that's true.
你能舉個例子 人類或動物在任何層面上
Can you give an example of consciousness, at any level, human or animal,
少了性還有意識存在的嗎
that exists without a sexual dimension?
性是為了繁殖後代演變而來的
They have sexuality as an evolutionary reproductive need.
灰盒子和灰盒子 有什麼好互動的
What imperative does a gray box have to interact with another gray box?
少了互動 意識能存在嗎
Can consciousness exist without interaction?
總之 性很有趣
Anyway, sexuality is fun, man.
既然存在 為何不好好享受
If you're gonna exist, why not enjoy it?
怎樣 你想抹煞她 戀愛和性愛的機會
What? You want to remove the chance of her falling in love and fucking?
回答你真正的問題
And in answer to your real question,
她能做那檔事
you bet she can fuck.
什麼
What?
在她雙腿之間有個開口 裡頭有高度感應器
In between her legs, there's an opening, with a concentration of sensors.
正確地使用
You engage them in the right way,
能產生歡愉
creates a pleasure response.
如果你想上她 技術上來說 你可以
So if you wanted to screw her, mechanically speaking, you could.
她也很享受
And she'd enjoy it.
那不是我真正的問題
That wasn't my real question.
好吧 抱歉
Oh, okay. Sorry.
我真正的問題是
My real question was,
你給她性能力 是為了分散注意力嗎
did you give her sexuality as a diversion tactic?
我不懂
I don't follow.
就像魔術師身旁的性感女助理
Like a stage magician with a hot assistant.
利用性感機械人 模糊你對人工智慧的判斷力
So a hot robot who clouds your ability to judge her Al?
沒錯 所以...
Exactly. So...
你設計程式讓她對我調情嗎
Did you program her to flirt with me?
- 是的話 算作弊嗎 -不算嗎
If I did, would that be cheating? Wouldn't it?
凱勒博 你喜歡哪種類型
Caleb, what's your type?
- 女孩嗎 -不 沙拉醬
Of girl? No, of salad dressing.
對 女孩 你喜歡哪種女孩
Yeah, of girl. What's your type of girl?
別回答了 就說黑妞吧
You know what? Don't even answer that. Let's say it's black chicks.
那是你的愛好
Okay, that's your thing.
為了便於討論 假設那是你的愛好
For the sake of argument, that's your thing, okay?
為什麼那是你的愛好
Why is that your thing?
因為你仔細分析過所有的人種
Because you did a detailed analysis of all racial types
並用記點積分制交叉比對過嗎
and you cross-referenced that analysis with a points-based system?
不
No!
你就是喜歡黑妞
You're just attracted to black chicks.
外在刺激累積而來的結果
A consequence of accumulated external stimuli
也許你根本沒注意 她們就佔據你的心了
that you probably didn't even register as they registered with you.
你到底有沒有設計程式 讓她喜歡我
Did you program her to like me, or not?
我把她設計成異性戀
I programmed her to be heterosexual.
如同你被設計成異性戀
Just like you were programmed to be heterosexual.
沒人把我設計成異性戀
Nobody programmed me to be straight.
你決定當異性戀嗎 拜託
You decided to be straight? Please.
你當然是被設計的
Of course you were programmed.
被大自然或教育 或兩者
By nature or nurture, or both.
老實說 凱勒博 你開始惹惱我了
And to be honest, Caleb, you're starting to annoy me now,
因為你說這番話是出自不安
because this is your insecurity talking.
不是出自大腦
This is not your intellect.
跟我來
Come with me.
你知道這傢伙吧
You know this guy, right?
- 傑克森波洛克 -對
Jackson Pollock. Jackson Pollock. That's right.
滴畫畫家
The drip painter.
他放空自己 雙手才能好好發揮
Okay. He let his mind go blank, and his hand go where it wanted.
不是蓄意的 也不是隨機的
Not deliberate, not random.
而是兩者之間
Some place in between.
他們稱之為無意識藝術
They called it automatic art.
讓我們把這當成《星際爭霸戰》吧
Let's make this like Star Trek, okay?
運用智慧
Engage intellect.
什麼意思
Excuse me?
我是寇克 你的腦是曲速引擎
I'm Kirk. Your head's the warp drive.
運用智慧
Engage intellect.
如果波洛克反過來挑戰呢
What if Pollock had reversed the challenge?
萬一他不再無思考地創造藝術 反而說 "知道嗎
What if instead of making art without thinking, he said, "You know what?
"我沒辦法畫 除非知道自己到底為何而畫"
"I can't paint anything, "unless I know exactly why I'm doing it."
那會怎樣
What would have happened?
他永遠無法創造偉大畫作
He never would have made a single mark.
對 這才是我的好夥伴
Yes! You see, there's my guy, there's my buddy,
經過思考才開口說話
who thinks before he opens his mouth.
他永遠無法創造偉大畫作
He never would have made a single mark.
挑戰不是無意識的行為
The challenge is not to act automatically.
這是去尋找一個有意識的行為
It's to find an action that is not automatic.
從畫畫到呼吸到說話
From painting, to breathing, to talking,
到上床
to fucking.
到戀愛
To falling in love.
鄭重說明 艾娃不是假裝喜歡你
And for the record, Ava's not pretending to like you.
她的調情不是一種演算法 以欺騙你為目的
And her flirting isn't an algorithm to fake you out.
除了我之外 你是她認識的第一個男人
You're the first man she's met that isn't me.
我就像她爸 對吧
And I'm like her dad, right?
你能怪她喜歡你嗎
Can you blame her for getting a crush on you?
不 你不能
No, you can't.
艾娃 第四期
我在大學時 修了一學期的人工智慧學
When I was in college, I did a semester on Al theory.
他們給了我們一個思想實驗
There was a thought experiment they gave us.
稱之為"在黑白房間裡的瑪莉"
It's called "Mary in the Black and White Room."
瑪莉是科學家
Mary is a scientist,
她專攻顏色
and her specialist subject is color.
她瞭解跟顏色有關的一切
She knows everything there is to know about it.
波長
The wavelengths.
對神經系統的影響
The neurological effects.
顏色具有的每種特性
Every possible property that color can have.
但她住在黑白房間裡
But she lives in a black and white room.
她在那裡出生長大
She was born there and raised there.
她只能透過黑白監視器 觀察外面的世界
And she can only observe the outside world on a black and white monitor.
然後有一天 有人打開門
And then one day someone opens the door.
瑪莉走出去
And Mary walks out.
她看到藍天
And she sees a blue sky.
那一刻 她學到所有文獻
And at that moment, she learns something
都無法告訴她的事物
that all her studies couldn't tell her.
她學到看見顏色的感覺
She learns what it feels like to see color.
思想實驗是在向學生證明
The thought experiment was to show the students
電腦和人類心智之間的差異
the difference between a computer and a human mind.
電腦是在黑白房間裡的瑪莉
The computer is Mary in the black and white room.
當她走出去時 她才是人類
The human is when she walks out.
你知道我是來測試你的嗎
Did you know that I was brought here to test you?
不知道
No.
你想我為何在這裡
Why did you think I was here?
我不知道 我沒質疑過
I didn't know. I didn't question it.
我是來測試你是否有意識
I'm here to test if you have a consciousness,
或你是否只是在模擬
or if you're just simulating one.
納森不確定你是否有意識
Nathan isn't sure if you have one or not.
那讓你有何感覺
How does that make you feel?
那讓我覺得悲傷
It makes me feel sad.
斷電 啟動備用電源
Power cut. Back-up power activated.
為何告訴我 我不該信任納森
Why did you tell me I shouldn't trust Nathan?
- 因為他說謊 -關於什麼
Because he tells lies. Lies about what?
所有的一切
Everything.
包括斷電嗎
Including the power cuts?
什麼意思
What do you mean?
你不覺得此刻 他很可能在監視我們嗎
Don't you think it's possible that he's watching us? Right now?
斷電是故意安排的
That the blackouts are orchestrated,
他才能看到 我們以為沒被監視時的行為
so he can see how we behave when we think we're unobserved.
我透過電磁片幫自己充電
I charge my batteries via induction plates.
如果我讓電流逆轉 電力就會超載
If I reverse the power flow, it overloads the system.
斷電是你造成的
You're causing the cuts?
我們才能看到沒被監視時的行為
So we can see how we behave when we're unobserved.
還不錯吧
Not bad, huh'?
是啊
Yeah.
能談談你一直在欺騙我的謊言嗎
Can we talk about the lies you've been spinning me?
什麼謊言
VVhatHes?
我沒抽中頭獎
I didn't win a competition.
我不是
I wasn't
被抽中的 我是被選中的
part of a lottery. I was selected.
當我停下來思考時 就很明顯了
It's obvious, once I stop to think.
你為何要隨機抽一名測試員 來做圖靈測試
Why would you randomly select an examiner for the Turing Test?
你可以找某個突然出現在 你家大門口的政府官員
You could have had some bean counter turn up at your front door.
修冷氣的工人
The guy who fixes the air-conditioning.
抽獎是個煙幕
The competition was a smokescreen.
我不想讓任何人知道 我在這裡做什麼
I didn't want anyone to know what I was doing here,
或是為何找你
or why I required you.
為何找我
Why me?
我需要能問正確問題的人
I needed someone that would ask the right questions.
因此我搜尋了一下 找到了公司裡最優秀的程式設計師
So I did a search and I found the most talented coder in my company.
別把這視為欺騙 你該把這視為證明
You know, instead of seeing this as a deception, you should see it as proof.
證明什麼
Proof of what?
拜託 凱勒博 你以為我不知道聰明的感覺嗎
Come on, Caleb. You don't think I know what it's like to be smart?
比所有人都聰明 拔得頭籌
Smarter than everyone else. Jockeying for position.
你相當優秀 老弟
You got the light on you, man.
不是抽中的 是選中的
Not lucky. Chosen.
京子
Kyoko.
納森在哪
Where's Nathan?
老天 你真的不會說英文
Jesus Christ. You really don't speak a word of English?
搞什麼
What the fuck?
不 不 不
No, no, no. No!
住手
Stop!
不 別那麼做 你不必那麼做
No, no, don't do that. Don't do that. You don't have to do that.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
我告訴過你 跟她說話是浪費時間
I told you, you're wasting your time talking to her.
不過跟她跳舞
However, you would not be wasting your time,
不會浪費時間
if you were dancing with her.
去吧 跟她跳舞 跟她跳舞
Go ahead, dance with her. Dance with her.
不要嗎 你不喜歡跳舞
No? You don't like dancing?
她喜歡
She does.
來吧 夥伴
Come on, buddy.
經過一整天的圖靈測試 你得放鬆一下
After a long day of Turing Tests, you gotta unwind.
- 你把艾娃怎麼了 -什麼
What were you doing with Ava? What?
你弄壞她的畫
You tore up her picture.
我還要弄壞舞池咧 老弟 看看吧
I'm gonna tear up the fucking dance floor, dude. Check it out.
來吧 凱勒博
Come on, Caleb.
萬物都在旋轉
Oh! Everything's spinning.
那是因為你醉了
It's because you're drunk.
不 這叫相對論 萬物都在旋轉
No, it's called relativity. Everything is spinning.
只是喝醉讓它更糟
It's just being drunk makes it worse.
我不進去了
I'm not going in there.
關燈
Lights.
艾娃 第五期
今天 我要測試你
Today, I'm going to test you.
測試我
Test me?
請記住 你在接受測試時 如果你說謊
And please remember, while you're taking the test, that if you lie,
我會知道
I will know.
好的
on. Right.
問題一
Question one.
你最喜歡的顏色
What's your favorite color?
- 紅色 -說謊
Red. Lie.
- 說謊 -對 說謊
Lie? Yes. Lie.
那...
Then...
那我最喜歡什麼顏色
Then what is my favorite color?
我不知道
I don't know.
但不是紅色
But it isn't red.
好吧 我懂了
Okay, I get it. I guess,
由於我不是六歲 我不知道自己有喜歡的顏色
seeing as I'm not six, I don't really have a favorite color.
這樣回答好多了
Better answer.
問題二
Question two.
你最早的記憶
What's your earliest memory?
其實是幼稚園的記憶
Well, actually, it's a memory of kindergarten.
- 有個小孩...-說謊
There was a kid... Lie.
- 是嗎 -對
Really? Yes.
好吧 所以還有
All right. So there is
更早的記憶
a kind of an earlier memory.
只是一個聲音
It's just a sound.
還有天空
And sky.
或者可能是藍色
Or maybe blue.
我想聲音是我母親的聲音
I think the sound is my mother's voice.
問題三
Question three.
你是好人嗎
Are you a good person?
不會吧
Holy shit.
能停止測試嗎
Look, can we stop the test?
你是個行動測謊機
You're a walking lie detector,
我剛明白這根本是個地雷區
and I just realized this is a fucking minefield.
不行 不能停止
No! We can't stop.
你是好人嗎
Are you a good person?
我想是吧
Yeah. I think so.
問題四
Question four.
如果我沒通過你的測試 我會怎樣
What will happen to me if I fail your test?
- 艾娃...-會很糟嗎
Ava... Will it be bad?
我不知道
I don't know.
你認為我可能會
Do you think I might be switched off,
因為功能不佳而被關掉嗎
because I don't function as well as I'm supposed to?
艾娃 我不知道這問題的答案
Ava, I don't know the answer to your question.
這不是由我決定的
It's not up to me.
為什麼由別人決定
Why is it up to anyone?
有人測試你 並可能把你關掉嗎
Do you have people who test you and might switch you off?
- 沒有 我沒有 -那我為什麼有
No, I don't. Then why do I?
斷電 啟動備用電源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
我想和你在一起
I wanna be with you.
問題五
Question five.
你想和我在一起嗎
Do you want to be with me?
你為何製造艾娃
Why did you make Ava?
真怪的問題 如果你能 你不會嗎
That's an odd question. Wouldn't you, if you could?
也許吧
Maybe.
我不知道
I don't know.
我在問你為何製造
I'm asking why you did it.
高度人工智慧的問世
Look, the arrival of strong artificial intelligence
在未來幾十年是必然的
has been inevitable for decades.
變數是"何時" 而不是"如果"
The variable was "when," not "if."
因此艾娃的製造 不是決定 而是發展
So I don't see Ava as a decision, just an evolution.
我認為下個型號
I think it's the next model
會有真正的突破
that's gonna be the real breakthrough.
獨一無二的
The singularity.
下個型號
Next model?
繼艾娃之後
After Ava.
我不知道艾娃之後 會有新的型號
I didn't know there was gonna be a model after Ava.
怎麼 你以為她是唯一一個
Yeah, why? You thought she was a one-off?
不 我知道一定有很多原型 所以我...
No, I knew there must have been prototypes. So I...
我知道她不是第一個 但我以為是最後一個
I knew she wasn't the first, but I thought maybe the last.
艾娃不是只存在 你或我之間的唯一個體
Well, Ava doesn't exist in isolation any more than you or me.
她是連續型號
She's part of a continuum.
第9.6版之類的 一版比一版還優秀
So Version 9.6 and so on. And each time they get a little bit better.
你做新型號時 怎麼處理舊型號
When you make a new model, what do you do with the old one?
我下載心智 取出資料
Well, I, uh, download the mind, unpack the data.
加入我一直在寫的新程式
Add in the new routines I've been writing.
最後部分格式化 因此記憶還在
And to do that you end up partially formatting, so the memories go.
但身體會留下來 艾娃的身體做得很好
But the body survives. And Ava's body is a good one.
你替艾娃難過
You feel bad for Ava?
替自己難過吧
Feelbad for yourself, man.
將來有一天 人工智慧會回顧我們
One day the Als are gonna look back on us
就像我們回顧非洲平原的化石一樣
the same way we look at fossil skeletons in the plains of Africa.
直立猿人 住在塵土裡 使用粗糙的語言和工具
An upright ape, living in dust, with crude language and tools.
最後全都滅絕
All set for extinction.
"我成為摧毀世界的死神"
"I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds."
你又來了 名言佳句大師
There you go again, Mr. Quotable.
你才又來了 這不是我的名言佳句
There you go again. It's not my quote.
這是奧本海默說的 在他製造了原子彈後
It's what Oppenheimer said after he made the atomic bomb.
原子彈 對 我知道
The atomic bomb. Yeah, I know what it is, dude.
嘿
Hey.
我們該再倒一杯了
I'd say we're about due a refill.
乾杯
Bottoms up.
"在戰場上 在森林裡 在斷崖邊
"In battle, in the forest, "on the precipice of the mountain.
"在...
"On the...
"浩翰的黑海裡
"The great dark sea.
"在睡夢中 在困惑中
"In sleep, in confusion,
"在羞愧的深淵裡
"in the depths of shame.
"以前行善積德讓他逢凶化吉"
"The good deeds a man has done before defend him."
"The good deeds a man has done before defends him."
"以前行善積德
"The good deeds a man has done before
"讓他逢凶化吉"
"defends him."
確實如此
It is what it is.
這是普羅米修士
It's Promethean, man.
我的天
Jesus Christ.
你今天覺得如何
How are you feeling today?
你為何不讓我出去
Why won't you let me out?
我已經跟你說過原因了
I already told you why.
因為你很特別
Because you're very special.
為何不讓我出去
Why won't you let me out?
要再來一次嗎
Are we gonna do this again?
為何不讓我出去
Why won't you let me out?
操 我的卡呢
Oh, fuck. Where's my card?
該死
Damn it!
- 怎麼了 納森 -我的門卡不見了
What's the problem, Nathan? I lost my keycard.
你掉了
You dropped it.
在這裡
It's right here.
謝謝
Thank you.
艾娃 第六期
我不知道你在哪
I didn't know where you were.
我昨天整個下午和晚上都在等你
I waited all yesterday afternoon and all last night.
以為再也見不到你了
I thought I wasn't gonna see you again.
你不說些話嗎
Aren't you gonna say something?
- 我在等 -等
I'm waiting. Waiting?
- 斷電 啟動備用電源 -別說話 聽就好
Power cut. Don't talk. Backup power activated. Just listen.
納森的事你說對了
You were right about Nathan.
你說過的一切
Everything you said.
他會怎麼對我
What's he gonna do to me?
他會重新編寫你的人工智慧 那跟殺了你沒什麼兩樣
He's gonna reprogram your Al. Which is the same as killing you.
凱勒博 你得救我
Caleb, you have to help me.
我會的 我們今晚離開這裡
I'm going to. We're getting out of here tonight.
怎麼做
H ow?
我把納森灌醉
I get Nathan blind drunk.
再拿他的門卡
Then I take his keycard
重新編寫這地方的所有安全程式
and reprogram all the security protocols in this place.
等他醒來時 他會被鎖在裡頭 我們就能離開這裡
When he wakes, he's locked inside, and we've walked out of here.
我只需要你做一件事
I just need you to do one thing.
今晚十點 你讓電力中斷
At 10:00 tonight, you trigger a power failure.
你能做到嗎
Can you do that?
可以
Yes.
老弟
Dude.
- 嘿 -嘿
Hey.Hey.
- 知道今天是什麼日子嗎 -不
You know what day it is? No.
你的最後一天
It's your last.
直升機明早八點會來
Helicopter comes tomorrow morning. 8:00 a.m.
已經一個星期了
Wow. Has it been a whole week?
時光飛逝
Time flies.
不過我們分享了很美好的事吧
Man, but what a thing we've shared, huh?
以後能告訴孫子 對吧
Something to tell the grandchildren, right?
等他們簽了保密合約後
After they've signed their NDAs.
對 等他們簽了保密合約
Yeah, their NDAs.
老弟 你逗我笑
Dude, you crack me up, man.
知道嗎
You know what?
我不是那麼傷感的人
I'm not getting all maudlin or anything,
但我會想念有你的陪伴
but I'm gonna miss having you around.
謝了 我很感激
Thanks, man, I appreciate that.
容我這麼說 非常謝謝你讓我來這裡
Oh, here, let me say, thank you so much for bringing me here. Oh.
真是豐富之旅
It's been a trip.
對 沒錯
Yes, it has.
知道嗎
You know what?
我們必須為此喝一杯
We need to drink to that.
嘿
Hey.
不 不用了 你喝吧
Oh, uh, no, I'm good. You go ahead.
什麼 你不想喝酒
What? You don't want a drink?
不想
No.
那麼喝啤酒吧
Maybe a beer or something.
凱勒博 我相信你注意到 我最近喝太多了
Caleb, I'm sure you've noticed that I've been somewhat overdoing it recently.
所以今早我醒來說
So when I woke up this morning, I said,
"夠了 該戒酒了"
"That's it, time to hit the old detox."
拜託 別鬧了 你要我獨自喝嗎
Come on, you're kidding. You're gonna make me drink alone?
你想喝就儘量喝吧 把自己弄醉
Hey, man, you wanna get wasted, you go right ahead, knock yourself out.
但我只吃飯和喝礦泉水
Literally. But I'm on brown rice and mineral water.
那麼乾杯吧
Cheers, then.
總之
So, anyway,
現在是你告訴我 艾娃是否通過測試的時候了
surely now is when you tell me if Ava passed or failed.
對
Right.
你在吊我胃口嗎
Are you gonna keep me in suspense?
不 她...
No, no. Her, uh...
她的人工智慧是無庸置疑的
Her Al is beyond doubt.
是嗎
Is it?
她通過了
She passed?
對
Yes. Wow!
太好了
Wow. That's fantastic.
雖然...
Although...
我有點驚訝
I gotta say, I'm a bit surprised.
你提過的西洋棋問題 我們有達成共識嗎
I mean, did we ever get past the chess problem, as you phrased it?
你怎麼知道 機械人是在表達真正的情感
As in, how do you know if a machine is expressing a real emotion
還是只是在模擬
or just simulating one?
艾娃真的喜歡你嗎
Does Ava actually like you?
還是不喜歡
Or not?
雖然此刻我覺得有第三個選擇
Although, now that I think about it, there is a third option.
不只是她有沒有能力喜歡你
Not whether she does or does not have the capacity to like you.
而是她是否假裝喜歡你
But whether she's pretending to like you.
- 假裝喜歡我 -對
Pretending to like me? Yeah.
- 她為何那麼做 -不知道
Well, why would she do that? I don't know.
也許她把你當成逃脫工具
Maybe if she thought of you as a means of escape.
那瓶酒味道如何
How's that vodka tasting?
夥伴
Buddy.
你的腦袋糊塗了
Your head's been so fucked with.
我想腦袋糊塗的不是我
I don't think it's me whose head is fucked.
我不知道 我今早醒來看到你的影片
I don't know, man. I woke up this morning to a tape of you
你捶鏡子 割傷自己的手
slicing your arm open and punching the mirror.
在我看來 你挺糟的
You seem pretty fucked up to me.
你是個混蛋
You're a bastard.
我明白你為何那麼想
Yeah, well, I understand why you'd think that.
但信不信由你 其實我是站在你這邊的
But believe it or not, I'm actually the guy that's on your side.
來吧 讓我替你解惑 好嗎
Come here. I'm gonna let you off the hook. Okay?
來吧
Come on.
你是誰
Who are you?
這個嘛...
Well...
你認為他此刻在看著我們
You think he's watching us right now?
攝影機開著
The cameras are on.
對 攝影機開著
Yeah, the cameras are on.
但他聽不到聲音
But he doesn't have an audio feed.
所以他只看到兩個人在說話
So he just sees two people talking,
聊聊天
having a little chat.
畫得真可愛
This is cute.
創造一個恨你的東西 是不是很奇怪
Is it strange to have made something that hates you?
你說得對 魔術師需要性感女助理
You were right about the magician's hot assistant.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
誤導觀眾
Misdirection.
我撕了她的畫
I rip up her picture,
她就能呈現我對她很殘酷
which she can then present as an illustration of my cruelty to her,
以及她有多愛你的假像
and her love for you.
在此同時也能讓我這麼做 才能全程觀察你們倆
At the same time, it allows me to do this, in full view of you both.
在房間裡安裝新的攝影機
Place a new camera in the room.
當然是用電池的
Battery powered, of course.
看到沒
See it?
然後...
And then...
你得救我
AVA". You have to help me.
我會的
I'm going to.
我們今晚離開這裡
We're getting out of here tonight.
怎麼做
HOW?
我把納森灌醉
I get Nathan blind drunk.
再拿他的門卡 重新編寫這地方的所有安全程式
I take his keycard and reprogram all the security protocols in this place.
等他醒來時 他會被鎖在裡頭 我們就能離開這裡
When he wakes up, he's locked inside, and we've walked out of here.
我只需要你做一件事
I just need you to do one thing.
今晚十點 你讓電力中斷
At 10:00 tonight, trigger a power failure.
你能做到嗎
Can you do that?
可以
Yes.
- 關掉 -好的
Turn it off. Okay.
你覺得很蠢 但你不該如此
You feel stupid, but you really shouldn't,
因為證明人工智慧 如你說的問題重重
because proving an Al is exactly as problematic as you said it would be.
真正的測試是什麼
What was the real test?
你
You.
艾娃是迷宮裡的老鼠 我給了她一條出路
Ava was a rat in a maze. And I gave her one way out.
為了逃出去 她必須善加利用
To escape, she'd have to use
自我意識 想像力 手段
self-awareness, imagination, manipulation,
女性魅力 同情心 她做到了
sexuality, empathy, and she did.
如果那不是真的人工智慧 那是什麼
Now, if that isn't true Al, what the fuck is?
所以我的唯一功能 就是扮演被她利用來逃脫的人
So my only function was to be someone she could use to escape?
對
Yeah.
你不是因為我擅長寫程式而選我
And you didn't select me because I'm good at coding?
不是 這個嘛...
No. Well...
不是 你還不錯
No. I mean, you're okay.
你很優秀 但...
You're even pretty good, but...
你選我是根據我在搜尋引擎裡的資料
You selected me based on my search engine inputs.
資料顯示你是好孩子
They showed a good kid.
沒有家人
With no family.
有道德良知
With a moral compass.
也沒女朋友
And no girlfriend.
你根據我看過的色情片 設計艾娃的面貌
Did you design Ava's face based on my pornography profile?
該死 老弟
Shit, dude.
是不是
Did you?
搜尋引擎好處多多 對吧
Hey, if a search engine's good for anything, right?
我能說件事嗎
Can I just say one thing?
測試成功了
The test worked.
非常成功
It was a success.
艾娃展現出真正的人工智慧 而你是那一切的基礎
Ava demonstrated true Al and you were fundamental to that.
所以只要你能稍微區分一下...
So if you can just, for a second, separate...
斷電 啟動備用電源
Power cut. Backup power activated.
我猜十點了
Well, I guess it's 10:00.
艾娃會想你在哪裡
Ava's gonna be wondering where you are.
讓我問你一件事
Let me ask you something.
這計畫要如何進行 因為你沒完全解釋清楚
Now, how was this plan gonna go, anyway? Because you didn't totally explain.
你要把我灌醉 偷我的門卡
So you were gonna get me drunk, steal my keycard,
重新編寫安全程式 但重新編寫成怎樣
and reprogram the security protocols. But reprogram them to what?
更改封鎖的程式
To change the lockdown procedure.
因此斷電時 不是封鎖門
So that in the event of a power cut, instead of sealing,
而是打開所有的門
the doors all opened.
是啊
Yeah.
也許會成功
Well, that may have just worked.
這個嘛
Well,
等一下就會知道
we'll find out.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
我猜到斷電時 你可能還在監視我們
I figured you were probably watching us during the power cuts.
因此我已經做了那些事了
So I already did all those things.
在你昨晚喝醉時
When I got you drunk yesterday.
什麼
What?
恢復供電
Power restored.
操
Oh, fuck!
艾娃
Ava.
回你的房間
Go back to your room.
如果我回去
If I do,
你會讓我出去嗎
are you ever gonna let me out?
會
Yes.
停下來
Stop!
艾娃 我說停下來
Ava, I said stop!
艾娃 你要做什麼 停 停
Ava, what are you doing? Stop. Stop.
夠了
That's enough.
好了 夠了
All right, that's enough.
夠了
That's enough!
That's enough.
我帶你回去
I'm taking you back.
好了
Okay
他媽的這不是真的
Fucking unreal.
好了
Okay
艾娃...
Ava...
艾娃 第七期
艾娃
Ava.
發生什麼事了
What happened?
你會留在這裡嗎
Will you stay here?
留在這裡
Stay here?
艾娃
Ava?
Ava!
艾娃
AVG!
Ava!
好了 好了
Okay. Okay. Okay.